Hello English Learners.
Welcome back to another
podcast here at English
Pod. My name is Marco.
And I'm Erica. And today
we have a fun dialogue.
That's right. Well, maybe
the language in this
lesson you won't use
every day, but it's fun.
It's interesting and it's a
little bit on the lighter side.
That's right. Today we're going to be
looking at baby talk. So we're going to see
some of these words
that aren't really words
and they're not real
words that you can find
in the dictionary, but
native English speakers
use them when they're
talking to little babies.
Yeah. In many
languages, there's there's a
rule for how you make
baby talk words, right?
Right. But in English,
we don't have really clear
rules about how you
make a word, a baby word.
So we're going to teach you
a few of these baby words.
Exactly. So before we
listen to the dialogue,
why don't we take a look at vocabulary
preview? Very vocabulary preview.
Okay. We have two words
here. We're going to hear
in the dialogue. And
the first one is diaper.
Diper. Diper. Okay. So a
diaper, a baby uses a diaper.
That's right. It's a piece of cloth or
material that you put around the baby so that
it can go to the bathroom
and not make a mess.
Okay, a diaper. Now we
also have another word
that we come in the use
in the English language.
It's nana. Nana.
So nana is the name we call a grandmother.
Right. So in an informal
name, just like in
Spanish, we would say
something like abuelita or an Italian.
You might say, oh,
ma, this is another
way that we can call a
grandma or granny, nana.
Okay. So nana. Why
don't we listen to the
dialogue for the first
time? Let's see how these
new parents are talking to
their little baby using baby talk.
Honey, the baby's up again.
It's your turn. I won't last night. Fine.
Hello, little baby. Why are you crying,
little baby? Oh, I see. You made a doo-doo.
What's going on, hun? Why is the baby
crying? The little baby made a doo-doo.
What a good boy. Let's
get this icky diaper off you.
Lucky what I have here.
Mickey Mouse jammies.
Oopsie daisy. Did the little
baby just tinkle all over daddy?
Yes, he did. Yes, he did.
He just made a wheelie all over daddy.
Oh, it's still while I
change his yucky diaper.
What's going on in here?
Oh, look, it's nana. Say hi to nana.
He's so adorable. I
could just eat him up.
Okay, say hi to nana.
Time to go, buddy, bye.
Okay, well, that was
pretty cute, wasn't it?
A cute dialogue at the
baby seemed to be cute,
and well, everyone's
excited about the new baby.
But they used some
really interesting little
words that are pretty unfamiliar. So let's
look at them now in language takeaway.
All right, so as we
mentioned before, these
words aren't actually
words that you won't find
them in the dictionary.
Right, but you'll hear
them commonly when
people are talking to babies,
and you might see them in a
movie or something like that.
So why don't we get
started with the first one?
All right, the first
word that may seem
a little bit strange.
The father said, hello,
whittle, baby, whittle,
baby. Okay, whittle.
So whittle is just a baby
talk way of saying little,
little, that's right.
Now the father saw that
the baby was crying
because he made a doo-do.
The baby made the
doo-do, not the father.
Right, the baby made a doo-do.
I do doo. Okay, so basically
a doo-do is when the baby
poos or poops in the diaper.
Okay, so, you know,
sometimes you go to the
bathroom and it might
take a little bit longer.
Exactly. That's
because of the doo-do.
The doo-do, right, the actual
technical or maybe the proper
English word for this
would be defecate. Okay,
so make a doo-do. All
right, now our third words
are interesting because
he said icky diaper.
That's right, an icky diaper.
And then he also said yucky.
So we've got two words here that mean the
same thing icky and yucky. And basically
means disgusting.
Right, something that's
really, really not nice. So
you would say icky or yucky.
Now these words have
other similar words.
We might recognize
ick or yuck. Right, so you
would use ick or yuck if
something is disgusting,
but when you're kind
of talking to a baby,
you would say icky,
yucky, smelly, adjective.
Now our next word, the father said
he has some icky mouse jammies.
Jammies. Okay, so
what are jammies?
Well, the word jammies
is short for pajamas.
Okay, pajamas. So the
clothes that you put on when
you go to sleep. Jammies.
Jammies. All right, and
now for our last two
words, they mean the same
thing as well. The little
baby tingled all over daddy.
So to tinkle. And then his mom
said a wee-wee all over daddy.
You made a wee-wee.
Okay, so tinkle and wee-wee.
Basically also going
to the bathroom,
but this time to pee. To
pee, exactly. To urinate.
Wee-wee. So the verb to
tinkle and the noun a wee-wee.
Very good. So these are
the words that we have for
you today in language.
Take away, as you can see,
they're kind of cute and
very common when you're
talking to babies and
you know, you have to be a
little bit nicer. Mm-hmm.
All right, so why
don't we listen to the
dialogue another time,
a little bit slower, and you'll
catch these words a little bit easier.
Honey. The baby's up again. It's your turn.
I wouldn't last night. Fine.
Hello, little baby. Why are you crying,
little baby? Oh, I see. You made a doo-doo.
What's going on, hun? Why is the baby
crying? The little baby made a doo-doo.
What a good boy.
Let's get this icky diaper off you.
Look at what I have here.
Mickey Mouse jammies.
Whoopsie daisy. Did the little
baby just tinkle all over daddy?
Yes, he did. Yes, he did. He just
made a wee-wee-wee-all over daddy.
Hold still while I change his yucky diaper.
Oh, what's going on in here?
Oh, look, it's Nana. Say hi to Nana. Oh,
he's so adorable. I could just eat him up.
Okay, say hi to Nana.
Time to go, buddy. Bye.
All right, so now
that we've seen those
great words, let's take
a look at two phrases
that we're going to look at now
in fluency builder. Fluency builder.
So the mother didn't really want to
get up and look after the baby. She said,
"It's your turn." It's your turn. It's your
turn. So when she says it's your turn.
That means you should do it now.
Right, so she's basically
saying now you have to do it.
I did it last time, so
now you have to do it.
It's your turn. That's
right, it's your turn.
And, well, the Nana,
the grandmother, she was
really, of course, she
really loves this little baby
and she said, "I
could just eat him up.
" I could just eat him
up. I could just eat him up.
Now, does she want to really eat him?
No, of course. Of course not.
What does she mean by
this? This is a phrase we
often use with very
cute things. It just means,
"Oh my god, he's so
cute." Okay, he's so cute that
I wish I could just hug
him and kiss him a lot.
Yes, we might use this with babies or maybe
with puppies. I could just eat him up.
All right, so great two
phrases that we've just
taken a look at. Let's
go back to our dialogue
for the last time and
then we'll come back
and talk a little bit
more about these babies.
Honey, the baby's up again. It's your turn.
I wouldn't last night. Fine.
Hello, little baby. Why are you crying,
little baby? Oh, I see. You made a doo doo.
What's going on, hun?
Why is the baby crying?
The little baby
made a doo doo doo.
What a good boy. Let's
get this icky diaper off you.
Lucky what I have here.
Mickey Mouse jammies. Whoopsie daisy.
Did the little baby just
tinkle all over daddy?
Yes, he did. Yes, he did.
He just made a wheelie.
All over daddy.
Hold still while I change his yucky diaper.
What's going on in here?
Oh, look, it's Nanna. Say hi to Nanna.
He's so adorable. I
could just eat him up.
Okay, say hi to Nanna.
Time to go, buddy. Bye.
Okay, so they are
obviously new parents.
They've just had a baby,
so they're excited about him.
Waking up and they're all excited about the
baby and how he wakes up and everything.
But an interesting thing, the
baby was sleeping in another room.
In English speaking
countries, people have sort
of two different opinions
about how you should
sleep with your baby. You
know, some people want
to have the baby in
the bed with them, right?
But some people think, no, the baby
should definitely sleep in its own room.
Okay, in another
room and in a crib.
Yeah, right. I think this
is a very important issue
because many people
consider that it's a good
thing for the baby to
sleep with the parents and
it feels safe and you can
make sure the baby's okay.
And it's easier for,
you know, waking up to
feed the baby and
change his diaper. Exactly.
And well, if the baby is
sleeping with its parents,
it might not wake up as
much. But other people
think if you let the baby
sleep with the parents,
the baby will become kind of
spoiled and not a very good baby.
Right, it might become too
dependent on the parents.
And for example, if you ever want to
go out or leave the baby with a baby
sitter or when the baby
starts maybe preschool or
kindergarten, it might
not be really independent.
So why don't you
tell us what you think?
Do you think it's a good
idea to allow a baby to sleep
with you or should sleep in its own room?
Yeah, you can tell us that our website,
EnglishPod.com, where you
can also ask any questions
you have about the
language in this dialogue.
All right, guys, so
we'll see you there.
And until next time, thanks
for downloading and goodbye.